100daysofrealfood.com 2019-03-31

# Privacy Policy » 100 Days of Real Food

__Date of Last Revision: May, 2018.__

100 Days of Real Food’s Privacy Policy is designed to help you (“User”) understand how we collect and use the personal information you decide to share, and help you make informed decisions when using our Web Site located at www.100daysofrealfood.com  (“WebSite”).

By using or accessing our Web Site, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us at policy{at}100daysofrealfood{dot}com. You are also encouraged to read our [Terms of Use](https://www.100daysofrealfood.com/terms-of-use/)

The Web Site is intended for use by persons 18 years and older. 100 Days of Real Food does not knowingly collect any information about children under the age of thirteen.

### Use And Disclosure Of Information

We will never share your email address or other private information with anyone without your permission.

If it is necessary to provide a service to you, we may request that you provide us with contact information sufficient to provide the service.  An example would be if you won a giveaway and the manufacturer needed to contact you to set up direct delivery (in which case permission is implied through participation in the contest).

100 Days of Real Food only shares personal information with third parties when we have a good faith belief that sharing the information is necessary to comply with the law; enforce or apply our Terms of Use including investigation of potential violations thereof; detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues; or protect the rights, property, or safety of 100 Days of Real Food, our Users, or others.  We do not sell, rent, share, or otherwise disclose personal information from Users for any commercial purpose. You will see a list of our third party service providers throughout this Privacy Policy.

100 Days of Real Food’s service provider (“Service Provider”) uses security measures to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of information under our control.  We store information in databases located in secured data centers with live personnel monitoring 24 hours a day, 7 days a week.  Data security is paramount, and our Service Provider is constantly re-evaluating and deploying, where appropriate, the latest technologies to enhance our security and the confidentiality of personal information.

We personally take additional security measures to block unauthorized access to our web platform including secure socket layer encryption, strong passwords, 2-step verification, and code to block brute force password cracking.

### **How We Use Cookies**

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

We use Google Analytics to analyze the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google’s privacy policy is available at: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>

Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can however obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:

(a) <https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en> (Chrome);

(b) <https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences>(Firefox);

(c) [http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/](https://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/) (Opera);

(d) <https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies> (Internet Explorer);

(e) <https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411> (Safari); and

(f) <https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy> (Edge).

Please note that blocking cookies may have a negative impact on the functions of many websites, including our Site. Some features of the Site may cease to be available to you.

### **Advertising**

This Site is affiliated with AdThrive, LLC (“AdThrive”) for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site.  AdThrive uses standard and widely-available tools for the placement and serving of ads, including those provided by Google, Inc. and its affiliates. We publish interest-based advertisements on the Site; that is, ads that are tailored to reflect your interests. To help understand your interests, AdThrive, Google and our other advertising partners will track your behaviour on our website and on other websites across the Internet using cookies.

By using this Site, you consent to the use of such cookies and the sharing of data captured by such cookies with AdThrive, Google, and our other third party partners.You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). You can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).  However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained.

For European Economic Area Residents

If you reside in a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), then under the GDPR and applicable data protection laws you have the rights, among other things, to access your personal data, have us erase it, and/or restrict its further processing.  If you wish to access or delete your personal data (if any) maintained by us or AdThrive related to advertising on the Site, you can contact AdThrive at info@adthrive.com. If you wish to see a list of the advertising partners we work with or change which of those partners track your behavior using cookies, click the ad preferences icon. (Available in the EU.)

### Email Addresses

We may collect your email address, but only if you voluntarily provide it to us. This may occur, for example, if you sign up to receive an email newsletter, or enter a promotion. We will use your email address for the purposes for which you provided it to us, and also from time to time to send you emails regarding the Site or other products or services that we believe may be of interest to you.  You may opt out of such email communications at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” button in the email.

We use a third party, ActiveCampaign, to provide this service to you, and to collect and store email addresses. You can view their privacy policy here – [ActiveCampaign’s Privacy Policy](https://www.activecampaign.com/privacy-policy/).

If you are a resident of a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), please refer to the section below entitled “Additional Rights of EEA Residents.”

### Registration or Account Data

We may collect other information from you when you register with our Site in order to use various features, such as our Free Membership area.  Such information could include your name, postal code and/or address, email, and password (if applicable). As you use the Site, we could collect other data that you provide voluntarily (such as comments that you post).

We may also collect information about you through other methods, including research surveys, and social media platforms.

We use a third party to provide the functionality to allow you to register for the Site, in which case the third party will also have access to your information. Otherwise, we will not provide any personally-identifying information about you to third parties, except if required by law. The third party that assists in the registration for the site, as well as in delivering certain downloadable content through email opt-ins, is ConvertFlow. You may view their privacy policy here – [ConvertFlow’s Privacy Policy](https://www.convertflow.com/terms-and-policies).

We may use your personally-identifying information for a variety of our internal business purposes, such as creating a better user experience for the Site, diagnosing and troubleshooting malfunctions on the Site, better understanding how the Site is used, and making personalized recommendations to you.

If you are a resident of a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), please refer to the section below entitled “Additional Rights of EEA Residents.”

### **Transactional Data**

We may process information relating to transactions, including purchases of goods and services, that you enter into with us and/or through our Site (“ **Transactional Data** “). The Transactional Data may include your contact details, your card details and the transaction details. The transaction data may be processed for the purpose of supplying the purchased goods and services and keeping proper records of those transactions.  Purchases and payment processing on our Site is handled by our payment services providers: Zapier, Stripe, PayPal. We will share transaction data with our payment services providers only to the extent necessary for the purposes of processing your payments, refunding such payments and dealing with complaints and queries relating to such payments and refunds. You can find information about the payment services providers’ privacy policies and practices here: [Zapier’s Privacy Policy](https://zapier.com/privacy/), [Stripe’s Privacy Policy](https://stripe.com/us/privacy) and [PayPal’s Privacy Policy](https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full).

### **Additional Rights of EEA (European Economic Area) Residents**

If you are a resident of a country in the EEA, you have the rights, among others, to:

(i)  access your personal data

(ii)  ensure the accuracy of your personal data

(iii) the right to have us delete your personal data

(iv)  the right to restrict further processing of your personal data, and

(v)  the right to complain to a supervisory authority in your country of residence in the event that data is misused

Further, you have the right to know what data we collect about you when you use the various parts of our Site.

(i) Free Membership Area: name and email address

(ii) Free Membership Opt-Ins to access free downloads and join our newsletter: name and email address

(iii) Waiting Lists for Real Lunches Real Easy or the Real Food Mini Pledge Program: name and email address

(iv) Real Lunches Real Easy downloads: transactional data as well as name, address, and email address

(v) Real Food Mini Pledge Program: transactional data as well as name, address, and email address

In all above examples, we collect your data to provide you with a service. In the case of the Free Membership area and newsletter email opt-ins, it is to provide you with valuable and useful resources as well as keep you update to date on weekly posts added to the blog. In the case of waiting lists, it is to be able to alert you when the named products are once again available for purchase. In the case of the products (Real Lunches Real Easy, and the Real Food Mini Pledge Program) it is to provide you with a useful and valuable resource that has been created to benefit you.

If you believe that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your residence, your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement.

You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal data by written notice to us addressed to the following:

Jason Leake

PO Box 78302

Charlotte, NC 28271

policy@100daysforealfood.com

### **Links to Other Websites**

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

### User Changes / Opting Out

Users may amend or remove any personal information they have provided to 100 Days of Real Food by contacting policy{at}100daysofrealfood{dot}com and describing the information they want removed.  Email subscribers can remove their subscriptions at any time and remove all personal information they have provided by emailing their desire to unsubscribe at the link provided in the email they receive.

### Revisions

We reserve the right to change our Privacy Policy at any time. Non-material changes and clarifications will take effect immediately, and material changes will take effect within 30 days of their posting on this site. If we make changes, we will post them and will indicate at the top of this page the policy’s effective date. We therefore encourage you to refer to this policy on an ongoing basis so that you understand our current privacy policy. Unless stated otherwise, our current privacy policy applies to all information that we have about you.
